Guide to the Anne LaBastille papers, 1963-2004
LaBastille, Anne papers,1963-2004
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Anne LaBastille papers, 1963-2004.
6420
Anne LaBastille
11 cubic ft.
Correspondence, fan mail, children's journals and letters, manuscripts, reviews, scrapbooks, artwork and photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Anne LaBastille papers include correspondence, fan mail, children's journals and letters, manuscripts, reviews, scrapbooks documenting publicity and promotion, as well as original artwork and photographs. Her papers clearly document the creative and publishing processes for Jaguar Totem, Woodswoman III, Birds of the Mayas, The Wilderness World of Anne LaBastille, Mama Poc, Beyond Black Bear Lake, and Women and Wilderness. Of particular interest is her extensive collection of letters from fans, which span her entire publishing career and includes letters and journals from children.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Anne LaBastille, is an ecological consultant, writer, photographer and lecturer, who obtained her Ph.D. from Cornell in Wildlife Ecology, following an M.S. in Wildlife Management from Colorado State University and a B.S. in Conservation of Natural Resources from Cornell. Currently president of West of the Wind Publications in Westport, New York, LaBastille has devoted her life to conservation of endangered wildlife, ecological studies of birds and mammals, preservation of wilderness and wildlands, international conservation projects, tropical rain forest, acid rain, and land and lake use planning. She is perhaps best known for her autobiographical Woodswoman trilogy, in which she explores her experiences building a cabin and leading a Thoreau-like existence in the Adirondacks. Woodswoman, Beyond Black Bear Lake, and Woodswoman III appeared in 1976, 1987, and 1997 respectively. Other publications include several non-fiction titles for children, Assignment: Wildlife, a book of essays, and Women and Wilderness, a series of profiles of wilderness women. In addition, she has published over 150 popular articles and more than 25 scientific papers.
A licensed Adirondack guide, LaBastille's research has taken her beyond the boundaries of the State Park to Central America, Panama, the Caribbean, South America, and the Florida Everglades. A member of the Wildlife Society, the Outdoor Writers Association of America, the Explorers Club, the Association for Tropical Biology, the Society of Women Geographers, the Cosmos Club and the New York State Outdoor Guides Association, LaBastille continues to research, write, publish and teach. She has won numerous awards, made numerous appearances on television and radio, and has lectured before a wide range of audiences.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Anne LaBastille papers include correspondence, fan mail, children's journals and letters, manuscripts, reviews, scrapbooks documenting publicity and promotion, as well as original artwork and photographs. Her papers clearly document the creative and publishing processes for Jaguar Totem, Woodswoman III, Birds of the Mayas, The Wilderness World of Anne LaBastille, Mama Poc, Beyond Black Bear Lake, and Women and Wilderness. Of particular interest is her extensive collection of letters from fans, which span her entire publishing career and includes letters and journals from children.
Includes letters to Nancy Kroening, 1980-2004
SUBJECTS
Names:
LaBastille, Anne.; Labastille, Anne. Assignment wildlife.; Labastille, Anne. Beyond Black Bear Lake.; Labastille, Anne. Birds of the Mayas.; Labastille, Anne. Jaguar totem.; Labastille, Anne. Mama Poc.; Labastille, Anne. Wilderness world of Anne Labastille.; Labastille, Anne. Women and wilderness.; Labastille, Anne. Woodswoman.; Labastille, Anne. Woodswoman III.; West of the Wind Publications, Inc.
Subjects:
Atitlan grebe.; Birds--Folklore.; Birds--Guatemala.; Birds--Mexico--Yucatan (State); Education--Children.; Environmental protection.; National parks and reserves--Panama.; Natural history--New York (State)--Adirondack Mountains.; Nature conservation.; Outdoor recreation for women--United States--History.; Publishers and publishing.; Self-publishing.; Women conservationists--United States--Biography.; Women naturalists--Biography.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Anne LaBastille papers, 1963-2000
  - Women and Wilderness: clippings, names and addresses, articles about interesting women., 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Women and Wilderness: clippings articles, addresses, etc., 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Magazines with articles on women, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Women in the Wilderness Quarterly: several issues, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Women in the Wilderness Quarterly: several issues; Women in Forestry, one issue, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Trade journals and book catalogs, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miscellany: clippings on outdoor women, news articles, ads for books, curriculum vitae, letters, etc., 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General articles on women: newsclippings, articles, newsletters, trips by women,Biruté Galdikas, Jane Goodall, Dian Fossey, Arlene Blum and others, 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General articles on women: newsclippings, articles, newsletters, trips by women, Margaret Martin, Linda R. Nelson, Clytia Montilor, Meridel LeSueur, Arlene Blum, Ethel Zoe Bailey, Dee Scarr, Idawalley Zorada Lewis, Bonnie Bordas and others, 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Women and Wilderness: information on women being considered, correspondence, 1977-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Women and Wilderness: general correspondence to find appropriate women, search for names on major organizations, charts on women selected, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Women and Wilderness: Sierra Club correspondence, general information, major letters and introductions, [advertisement used to find] the women, Louise Bogan poem, 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General: articles on remarkable women, correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Women and Wilderness: research and correspondence, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ballard, Jean: research notes, correspondence, 1953-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bass, Joan: research notes, correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Beck, Anne: research notes, correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bentley, Barbara: research notes, correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Carr, Marjorie: research notes, correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cerulli, Mary: research notes, correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Clark, Eugenie: research notes, correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Cohen, Diana: research notes, correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Daniels, Joan: research notes, correspondence; Women and Wilderness ch. 13 ms. draft, 26 pp; second ch. 13 ms. draft with Daniels' comments, 20 pp., 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Duplaix, Nicole: research notes, correspondence; Women and Wilderness ch. 15 ms. draft, 15 pp; second ch. 15 ms. draft with Duplaix's comments, 12 pp., 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Earle, Sylvia: research notes, correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Eckel, Peggy: research notes, correspondence; Women and Wilderness chapter 5 outline, 6 pp; ch. 5 ms. draft, 22 pp; second ch. 5 draft with Eckel's comments, 12 pp., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Gurnee, Jeanne: research notes, correspondence; Women and Wilderness ch. 7 outline, 6 pp; ch. 7 ms. draft with Gurnee's corrections, 16 pp., 1967-1981 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Hillman, Kes: research notes, correspondence, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Johnson, Krissa: research notes, correspondence; Women and Wilderness ch. 4 outline, 12 pp; ch. 4 ms. draft, 18 pp; second ch. 4 ms. draft with Johnson's corrections, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Kopelo, Suzanne: research notes, correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lawton, Rebecca: research notes, correspondence; Women and Wilderness ch. 10 outline, 12 pp; ch. 10 ms. draft, 18 pp; second ch. 10 ms. draft with Lawton's corrections, 18 pp., 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Link, Sheila: research notes, correspondence; Women and Wilderness ch. 8 outline, 10 pp; ch. 8 ms. draft, 21 pp; second ch. 8 ms. draft with Link's corrections, 11 pp., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Mattson, Ursula: research notes, correspondence, photos of Mattson, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Murie, Margaret: research notes, correspondence, 1978-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Nichols, Holly: research notes, correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Nichols, Jean Ann: research notes, correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Nichols, Maggie: research notes, correspondence; Women and Wilderness ch. 18 outline, 6 pp; ch. 18 ms. draft, 15 pp; second ch. 18 ms. draft with Nichols' corrections, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Owings, Margaret: research notes, correspondence; Women and Wilderness ch. 11 outline, 12 pp; ch. 11 ms. draft, 26 pp; second ch. 11 ms. draft with Owings' corrections, 19 pp., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Rhode, Elaine: research notes, correspondence; Women and Wilderness ch. 12 outline, 10 pp; ch. 12 ms. draft, 25 pp; second ch. 12 ms. draft with Rhode's corrections, 20 pp., 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Rona, Donna: research notes, correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Ruckdeschel, Carol: research notes, correspondence; Women and Wilderness ch. 14 outline, n.p.; ch 14 ms. draft, 26 pp., 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Stone, Doris: research notes, correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Stewart, Margaret: research notes, correspondence; Women and Wilderness ch. 3 outline, n.p.; ch. 3 ms. draft, 20 pp; second draft with Stewart's corrections, 15 pp., 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Taylor, Valerie: research notes, correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Zuchert, Judi: research notes, correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Women not included in final selection, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 1 ms., 19 pp; photo of Margaret Mead and Jeanne Gurnee, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 3 ms., 20 pp; photo of Dr. Margaret Stewart, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 4 ms., 12 pp; photo of Krissa Johnson, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 5 ms., 12 pp; photo of Peggy Eckel, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 6 ms., 18 pp; photos of Carol Ruckdeschel, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 8 ms., 11 pp; photo of Sheila Link, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 9 ms., 19 pp; photos of Diana Cohen, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 10 ms; photos of Rebecca Lawton, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 11 ms., 19 pp; photos of Margaret Owings, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 12 ms., 20 pp; photos of Elaine Rhode, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 13 ms., 20 pp; photos of Joan Daniels, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 14 ms., 23 pp; photos of Margaret Murie, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 15 ms., 17 pp; photos of Nicole Duplaix, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Women and Wilderness: ch. 18 ms., 14 pp; photos of Maggie Nichols, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Mama Poc: original ms. (n.p.) and corrections; many misc. notes and changes, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Mama Poc: selected ch.s (n.p.) work with editor, Carol Smith, especially the epilogue;" correspondence, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Mama Poc: ms. missing epilogue, pp. 1-146, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Mama Poc: ms. missing epilogue, pp. 147-243, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Mama Poc: ms. missing epilogue, pp. 244-321, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Mama Poc: ms., pp. 1-146, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Mama Poc: ms., pp. 147-248, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Mama Poc: ms., pp. 249-342; "few loose pages at end, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Mama Poc: draft maps of lake, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Mama Poc: captions and photos, credit lines and some letters, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Mama Poc: original letters of permission, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Mama Poc: miscellaneous: Grebe postage stamps and information, style sheet, logo with Poc, photo for back cover," [Ramiro Castillo World Wildlife Federation (WWF) letter of honor, article in WWF newsletter], 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Wildlife Monographs: 66 pp., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Banco Industrial, S.A.: 1988 Annual Report, 83 pp.], 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Mama Poc: correspondence with Carol Smith, W. W. Norton editor; David Allen, photographer; Julian Bach, Literary Agent; Jane Kinne, Comstock Agency Photo Agent; misc. quotations, maps, acknowledgements, papers, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Mama Poc: page proofs, pp. 1-149, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mama Poc: page proofs, pp. 150-315; list of captions, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Wilderness World of Anne LaBastille: rejected sections, ms., n.p., 1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Wilderness World: covers, contents, and advertisements, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Wilderness World: cut page proofs, 118 pp., 1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Wilderness World: cut page proofs, 118 pp., 1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Wilderness World: bluelines, 118 pp., 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - LaBastille's publicity scrapbook, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - LaBastille's publicity scrapbook, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - LaBastille's publicity scrapbook, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - LaBastille's publicity scrapbook, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Birds of the Mayas: artwork by Dr. W. Dilger and Anne LaBastille. "This artwork dates from 1963-64, for first version of book, done by Valley Press in Deposit, NY, and using my married name Bowes.", 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Mayan stories, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Birds of the Mayas: art work and Mayan names of (and stories about) birds. 15 final drawings of birds by Anne LaBastille and used in 1964 and 1993 editions, 1964 and 1993 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Birds of the Mayas: galleys, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Birds of the Mayas: first edition, 50 pp., 1964 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Mayan miscellany: Mayan glyphs copied by LaBastille, Mayan vocabulary list], "Map of Mayaland", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Birds of the Mayas: miscellaneous art work, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous corrections: bird names and research notes, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Birds of the Mayas: Cynthia Berger's copy-edited version of 'Check List of Birds', 1993 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Birds of the Mayas: correspondence, corrections, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Birds of the Mayas: travel plans for Mexico, miscellaneous printing costs, full color cover and printing instructions, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Birds of the Mayas: partial draft ms. typed by friend in Old Forge, n.p.; with corrections, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Birds of the Mayas: page proofs with corrections, n.p.; correspondence, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Birds of the Mayas: faxes, text from Doris Herwig, n.p.; with corrections, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Notes: Federal Express envelope with notes, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Birds of the Mayas: page proofs with corrections, pp. 1-28; correspondence, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Birds of the Mayas: page proofs with corrections, pp. 29-120; correspondence, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Birds of the Mayas: page proofs with corrections, n.p.; correspondence, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Birds of the Mayas: page proofs with corrections, n.p., 1993 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Birds of the Mayas: page proofs with corrections, n.p., 1993 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Birds of the Mayas: covers mailed as advertisements, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Birds of the Mayas: sales correspondence, book cover, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Birds of the Mayas: sales correspondence, advertisement, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Birds of the Mayas: mockup, some cover information, miscellaneous faxed corrections, 104 pp., 1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Birds of the Mayas: first edition, 120 pp., 1993 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Woodswoman III: outline, n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Woodswoman III: preliminary outlines, correspondence, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Woodswoman III: original yellow pad and pen ms. to starting, n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Woodswoman III: original ms., n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Woodswoman III: original ms., n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Woodswoman III: ms. #1, n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Woodswoman III: changes for draft #1, n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Woodswoman III: early ms. with corrections, n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Woodswoman III: extra [copies], early stages, n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Woodswoman III: list of changes, drafts, early ms., n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Woodswoman III: very early ms. with 3 chapters missing ...typed by Ms. Kassin...corrections..."by a friend, Dan, English teacher and Cornell PhD." No photos, table of contents, etc. n.p., 1996 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Woodswoman III: extra ch.s, many heavily corrected, no order, early stage, n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Woodswoman III: ms., several versions of each chapter with changes, early stages, n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Woodswoman III: midstage complete ms. "sent to my oldest chum, Mary Jane, from high school days and also a writer, for review"; no photos, artwork, title pages, etc., yet; chapter order changed later, n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Woodswoman III: midstage ms.; corrections; n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Woodswoman III: complete typed ms. in midstage; no photos, or beginning pages 1-20, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Woodswoman III: proposal sent to agent and turned down n.p., 1996 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Woodswoman III: complete ms., synopsis, table of contents, mid to late stage, n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Woodswoman III: extra ch.s, no order, n.p., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Woodswoman III: ms. draft #2, n.p., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Woodswoman III: ms. draft #2 with corrections, n.p., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Woodswoman III: ms. draft #2 with corrections, n.p., 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Woodswoman III: final ms. with copy editor's corrections, n.p., 1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Woodswoman III: final hard copy, ms., n.p., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Woodswoman III: ms. with copy editor's changes and style sheet, n.p., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Woodswoman III: photos and captions n.p., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Woodswoman III: page proofs with corrections, 256 pp., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Woodswoman III: development of front and back covers, correspondence, photo of LaBastille, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Woodswoman III: bluelines, 255 pp., 1997 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Woodswoman III: advertising, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Woodswoman III: plans for party celebrating publication, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Assignment: Wildlife: correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Assignment: Wildlife: general research, correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Assignment: Wildlife: photocopy with new chapters, correspondence, 1980, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Assignment: Wildlife: photocopy with new chapters, correspondence, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Assignment: Wildlife: correspondence, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Jaguar Totem: information to update original Assignment: Wildlife chapters, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Jaguar Totem: early outline, notes, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Jaguar Totem: correspondence, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Jaguar Totem: foreword with corrections, 3 pp., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Jaguar Totem: correspondence, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Jaguar Totem: early manuscript with corrections, pp. 1-171, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Jaguar Totem: early manuscript with corrections, pp. 172-303, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Jaguar Totem: early manuscript with corrections, pp. 1-179, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Jaguar Totem: early manuscript with corrections, pp. 180-226, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Jaguar Totem: ms. with corrections, pp. 1-174, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Jaguar Totem: ms. with corrections, pp. 175-240, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Jaguar Totem: late ms. with corrections, pp. 1-156, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Jaguar Totem: late ms. with corrections, pp. 157-304, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Jaguar Totem: acknowledgements, n.p.; memorial. n.p.; afterword, 6 pp.; corrections, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Jaguar Totem: photo and captions list, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Jaguar Totem: correspondence, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Jaguar Totem: corrections, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Jaguar Totem: page proofs with corrections, pp. 1-166, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Jaguar Totem: page proofs with corrections, pp. 167-275, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Jaguar Totem: page proofs with corrections, pp. 1-144, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Jaguar Totem: page proofs with corrections, pp. 145-267, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Jaguar Totem: corrections, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Jaguar Totem: corrections, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Jaguar Totem: corrections, correspondence, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Jaguar Totem: mockup, pp. 1-20, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Jaguar Totem: card stock cover samples, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Jaguar Totem: cover designs, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Jaguar Totem: back cover blurb, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Jaguar Totem: bluelines, 269, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Jaguar Totem: advertising, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Cornell Chronicle: announcements of Jaguar Totem, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Jaguar Totem: fan mail, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Woodswoman: softcover, 277 pp., 1976 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - La Donna Dei Bosch: softcover, 339 pp., 1990 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Assignment: Wildlife: hardcover, 243 pp., 1980 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Women and Wilderness: hardcover, 310 pp., 1980 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Women and Wilderness: softcover, 310 pp., 1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Women and Wilderness: Japanese translation, hardcover, 358 pp., 1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Beyond Black Bear Lake: hardcover, 251 pp., 1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Beyond Black Bear Lake: softcover, 251 pp., 1988 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Beyond Black Bear Lake: signed softcover, 251 pp., 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Beyond Black Bear Lake: German translation, hardcover, 205 pp., 1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Mama Poc: hardcover, 313 pp., 1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Mama Poc: softcover, 313 pp., 1991 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Mama Poc: Italian translation, softcover, 353 pp., 1991 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Mama Poc: German translation, softcover, 416 pp., 1992 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Mama Poc: Japanese translation, hardcover, 304 pp., 1994 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - The Wilderness World of Anne LaBastille: softcover, 118 pp., 1992 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Woodswoman III: softcover, 250 pp., 1997 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Jaguar Totem: softcover, 269 pp., 1999 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - National Geographic magazines, 1975, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Fan Mail, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 16-18)
  - Fan Mail, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 19-22)
  - Fan Mail, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 23-25)
  - Fan Mail, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Fan Mail, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
  - Fan Mail, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 4-8)
  - Fan Mail, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 9-12)
  - Fan Mail, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 13-15)
  - Fan Mail, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 16-18)
  - Fan Mail, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 19-20)
  - Fan Mail, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Fan Mail, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 22-24)
  - Fan Mail, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 25-26)
  - Fan Mail, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 27-30)
  - Fan Mail, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 31-33)
  - Fan Mail, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 34-35)
  - Fan Mail, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Fan Mail, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Fan Mail, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Fan Mail, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Fan Mail, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Fan Mail, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 41)